we also need investments in research and development. So what might that look like? In 1966, the US invested about a half a percent of gross domestic product in the Apollo program. It got people safely to the moon and back to the earth. Half a percent of GDP today is about 100 billion dollars. So knowing that direct air capture is one front in our fight against climate change, imagine that we could invest 20 percent, 20 billion dollars. Further, let's imagine that we could get the costs down to a 100 dollars a ton. That's going to be hard, but it's part of what makes my job fun. And so what does that look like, 20 billion dollars,100 dollars a ton? That requires us to build 200 synthetic forests, each capable of capturing a million tons of CO2 per year. That adds up to about five percent of US annual emissions. It doesn't sound like much. Turns out, it's actually significant. If you look at the emissions associated with long-haul trucking and commercial aircraft, they add up to about five percent. Our dependence on liquid fuels makes these emissions really difficult to avoid. So this investment could absolutely be significant. Now, what would it take in terms of land area to do this, 200 plants? It turns out that they would take up about half the land area of Vancouver. That's if they were fueled by natural gas. But remember the downside of natural gas -- it also emits CO2. So if you use natural gas to do direct air capture, you only end up capturing about a third of what's intended, unless you have that clever approach of co-capture that Carbon Engineering does. And so if we had an alternative approach and used wind or solar to do this, the land area would be about 15 times larger, looking at the state of New Jersey now. One of the things that I think about in my work and my research is optimizing and figuring out where we should put these plants and think about the local resources available -- whether it's land, water, cheap and clean electricity -- because, for instance, you can use clean electricity to split water to produce hydrogen, which is an excellent, carbon-free replacement for natural gas, to supply the heat required. But I want us to reflect a little bit again on negative emissions. Negative emissions should not be considered a silver bullet, but they may help us if we continue to stall at cutting down on CO2 pollution worldwide. But that's also why we have to be careful. This approach is so alluring that it can even be risky, as some may cling onto it as some kind of total solution to our climate crisis. It may tempt people to continue to burn fossil fuels 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. I argue that we should not see negative emissions as a replacement for stopping pollution, but rather, as an addition to an existing portfolio that includes everything, from increased energy efficiency to low-energy carbon to improved farming -- will all collectively get us on a path to net-zero emissions one day. A little bit of self-reflection: my husband is an emergency physician. And I find myself amazed by the lifesaving work that he and his colleagues do each and every day. Yet when I talk to them about my work on carbon capture, I find that they're equally amazed, and that's because combatting climate change by capturing carbon isn't just about saving a polar bear or a glacier. It's about saving human lives. A synthetic forest may not ever be as pretty as a real one, but it could just enable us to preserve not only the Amazon, but all of the people that we love and cherish, as well as all of our future generations and modern civilization. Thank you. (Applause)
también necesitamos invertir en investigación y desarrollo. ¿Cómo sería esto? En 1966, EE. UU. invirtió un 0,5 % de su PIB en el programa Apolo. Llevó personas a la luna ida y vuelta, de manera segura. Hoy en día, 0,5 % del PIB son unos USD 100 mil millones. Sabiendo que la captura directa de aire es uno de los frentes de nuestra lucha contra el cambio climático, imaginen si pudiéramos invertir el 20 %, es decir, USD 20 mil millones. Es más, imaginemos si podemos reducir los costos a USD 100 la tonelada. Será difícil, pero es lo que hace que mi trabajo sea interesante. ¿Cómo sería USD 20 mil millones a USD 100 la tonelada? Para ello, hay que construir 200 bosques sintéticos, cada uno con capacidad de capturar un millón de toneladas de CO2 por año. Eso representa cerca del 5 % de las emisiones anuales en EE. UU. No parece mucho, pero es, en realidad, muy significativo. Las emisiones generadas por el transporte de larga distancia y las aerolíneas comerciales, suman alrededor del 5 %. Nuestra dependencia de los combustibles líquidos hace que estas emisiones sean muy difíciles de evitar. Así que esta inversión podría ser completamente significativa. ¿Qué superficie terrestre se necesitaría para hacer esto? Doscientas plantas, que ocuparían cerca de la mitad de la superficie de Vancouver. Esto, si funcionaran a gas natural. Pero recuerden que la desventaja del gas natural es que también emite CO2. Y si usamos gas natural para capturar CO2 directamente del aire, acabaremos captando alrededor de un tercio de lo que se pretende, a menos que se use el sistema inteligente de la cocaptura aplicado por "Carbon Engineering". Si tuviéramos un sistema alternativo y utilizáramos energía eólica o solar, la superficie debería ser 15 veces mayor, como el tamaño de Nueva Jersey. Una de los temas que me ocupan en mi trabajo y en mi investigación es optimizar estas plantas y evaluar dónde instalarlas y pensar en los recursos locales disponibles, ya sea tierra, agua, electricidad asequible y no contaminante. Se puede usar, por ejemplo, electricidad no contaminante para separar el agua y producir hidrógeno, que es un sustituto excelente del gas natural -- libre de carbono, además -- para suministrar el calor necesario. Pero quiero que reflexionemos de nuevo sobre las emisiones negativas. Las emisiones negativas no deben considerarse un remedio milagroso, pero pueden ayudarnos si seguimos atascados a la hora de reducir la polución de CO2 a nivel mundial. Por eso tenemos que tener cuidado. Este método es tan atractivo que hasta puede ser riesgoso, pues algunos pueden aferrarse a él como si fuera la solución definitiva a la crisis climática. Puede tentar a la gente a quemar combustibles fósiles 24 horas al día, 365 días al año. No deberíamos considerar las emisiones negativas como un sustituto para detener la polución, sino como un elemento más de un portafolio que ya existe y que incluye todo, desde una mayor eficiencia energética, al carbono de bajo consumo, a la agricultura mejorada. Algún día, todo esto nos llevará al camino de las emisiones negativas. Un poco de autorreflexión. Mi marido es médico de urgencias. Y me maravilla el trabajo que él hace con sus colegas para salvar vidas todos los días. Y cuando hablo con ellos de mi trabajo para capturar carbono, veo que ellos también se maravillan. Y eso es porque combatir el cambio climático capturando el carbono, no se trata solo de salvar un oso polar o un glaciar. Se trata de salvar vidas humanas. Puede que un bosque sintético nunca llegue a ser tan bello como uno de verdad, pero podría permitirnos preservar no solo el Amazonas sino a todas las personas que queremos y valoramos, además de las generaciones futuras y la civilización moderna. Gracias. (Aplausos)